## **Christopher Pitts**

503-567-0026 | cphpitts@gmail.com cphpitts.github.io | linkedin.com/in/cphpitts | github.com/cphpitts

#### About Me

For more than 10 years I have developed a wide range of skills including graphic design, web management, software development, and project management. My desire to continuously learn and grow both personally and professionally has helped me to continue to thrive in new environments and with teams of all sizes. I am excited to continue my journey and do amazing things with you.

### Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, C#, SQL

Frameworks/ Libraries: Django, ASP.Net, Bootstrap, jQuery, Knockout.js, Node.js, Socket.io

IDEs: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio 2019, PyCharm, Atom

Methodologies: Agile, Scrum

Graphic Design: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Photoshop

CMS: Magento, Miva Merchant Business Domains: eCommerce

# **Experience Summary**

**Python/ Django:** Developed collection tracking application using Django framework in Visual Studio Code. This application included database management, scraping XML from an API call and using BeautifulSoup to scrape HTML for content. Additional experience includes developing an application to sort and delete files from a provided directory using PyCharm.

**C#/ ASP.Net:** Collaborated with a team of developers to add features to a local theatre website in Visual Studio 2019. Tasks included modifying the messaging page to display deleted messages and provide search functionality as well as modify how images were uploaded and displayed. These tasks involved modifying the model structure, creating new controller functions and editing view pages.

**Javascript:** Developed multiple applications to assist in playing role playing games remotely. Applications include a virtual tabletop tun using Node.js that utilizes Socket.io to enable real-time interaction between players to track dice rolls and encounter progress. Have also used Knockout.js to develop a proof of concept for a character generation application.

## Job History

#### Prosper IT | Portland OR

Intern | July 2020 - August 2020

- Developed features for MVC website designed for local theatre with ASP.Net framework
- Modified model structure and created new controller methods to display trashed messages
- Added features to admin dashboard to allow for easier editing of page information
- Identified and fixed bugs regarding deletion of production data

#### MyBinding.com | Beaverton, OR

Marketing Team Lead | April 2015 - February 2020

- Managed development and marketing teams of Magento eCommerce website
- Developed front end features with Javascript and jQuery including tracker for coupon codes and sticky navigation bar.
- Implemented installation and management of vendor application applications including search providers, popup modals and cart reminders.
- Generated weekly and monthly sales reports for online and inside sales departments.

#### Education

#### The Tech Academy

Software Development Bootcamp | 2020

Developed a fundamental knowledge of software development including usage of HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python and C#. Additional instruction included database management and design, SQL, source control, Scrum/Agile, object-oriented programming and computer science.

#### California State University, Fresno

B.A. Art - Graphic Design | 2002 - 2006

Developed skills in graphic design including print and web design.